

Mobile: + (92) 335-1287527 Phone: Email: anwar.mohiuddin77@gmail.com anwar_mf2003@yahoo.com

Anwar Mohiuddin

Objective:

To attain a key position in your organization that provides opportunities for learning, growth, teamwork, personal and professional development and valuable contribution towards the overall enhancement of the organization.

Professional Profile:

Performance-driven, professional with 16 years of continuous advancement. **P**roactive self-starter with track record of initiative, personal responsibility, ownership of work and reputation for removing obstacle and making things happen.

Creative, dependable, and enthusiastic change agent with proven track record in improving efficiencies, Computer- literate performer with extensive technical proficiency covering wide range of applications and platforms, including MS Excel, MS Word and JD Edwards Enterprise One 8.12 ERP Software).

Areas of Expertise:

Strong financial accounting knowledge to Control & process the accounts operation according to the appropriate accounting policies and procedures. Lead the Audit function of entire organization, Planning audits, reviewing internal controls, conducting audit tests, documenting audit issues, and following up on outstanding tasks and audit issues under supervision of domain owner.

Execute and implement agreed audit programs by maintaining relations with audited departments in order to obtain access to their documentation, reports, systems and personnel.

Efficient user of Oracle JD Edwards Enterprise One 8.12 (Financial Accounting & Reporting ERP Software) Monitoring of General Ledger Activities for the accuracy and completeness of company financials.

Professional Experience:

Fotile Kitchen & Home App. Pvt., Ltd. (Karachi) May 2017 – Present

Position: Senior Account Executive

Currently associates with Fotile Kitchen and Home Appliances, one of the most famous household brand in the China kitchen appliance industry and has to-date successfully entered into more than 20 overseas markets.

Overseeing following Accounting areas including;

- Day to day finance and accounts operations, handling of financial accounting role e.g. AR, AP, GL, etc.
- Preparation of Bank & Cash Payment/ Receipt vouchers, Verifies bank accounts, checks reports for accuracy of posting and calculation and performs other such work.
- Preparation of bank and general ledger reconciliations.
- Inventory management.
- Treasury Management and Management reports.
- Manage accounting assistants and bookkeepers.
- Play key role implementation of internal control of all the financial transaction.
- Spot errors and suggest ways to improve efficiency and spending.
- Assist in other tasks assigned by the management time to time.

Ammar Group of Companies (Karachi)

Jan 2016 – Apr 2017

Position: Senior Accountant

Currently associates with Ammar Advertiser (Hoarding & Billboards Advertising), overseeing following Accounting areas including; Accounts Payable, Treasury Management, General Ledger and Management reporting in a different time period.

Malik Corporation (Karachi)

April 2013 to Dec 2015

"Only Sole Agent in Pakistan CPVC, UPVC Pipes and Fittings of AGM Brand".

Position: Senior Management Accountant

- Responsible for Accounts Payable, GL, Tax functions, month end closing and overall Financial & Management Reporting.
- Supervise the input and handling of all company financial data and reports generated by the company's automated financial systems.
- Handling Special investigative assignment in Internal Audits i.e., internal business process, Inspection, documents verification, executing physical audit.
- Supervising the system efficiency and effectiveness of audit.
- Conducting audits of various departments to ensure inventory controls,
 Investigate and rectify routine errors and anomalies in the data and reports monthly, quarterly, and annual closing of accounts.

Radwa Food Production Co. Ltd., (Jeddah, Saudi Arabia)

Mar 2004 to Jan 2012

"Radwa Food Prod. Co" a dominant player in the premium quality poultry segment in Saudi Arabia, and part of the innovative and diverse (Aal Taher Group).

Position: Senior Account Supervisor

- Monitoring all the purchases and payments of company ensuring efficient utilization of the company's funds.
- Control the Treasury operation, prepare the Forecast/ Cash Flow reports.
- Monthly Bank reconciliation.
- Pass the necessary adjustments and corrections entries in various accounts and update the schedules accordingly.
- Accounts Reconciliation and responsible for month end closing & Management Reporting.
- Open LC's & LG's and Liaison with the Financial Institution, prepare the schedules and record in the books accordingly.

Dairy Food Industries, Karachi Pakistan.

Jan 00 to Feb 03

"Dairy Food Industries" One of the best industries for the premium quality dairy foodstuff in Pakistan, a variety of products are: Milk, Yogurt, Creams, Tea Milk, Powder Milk, Beverage and Ice Cream etc.

Position: Account Assistant

Pakistan Steel Fabricating Co., (Pvt.) Ltd.

Oct 96 to Oct 99

"Pakistan Steel Fabricating" A subsidiary company of Pakistan Steel Mills Corporation Ltd. Ministry of production, government of Pakistan.

Position: Account Assistant

Qualification:

Bachelor of Commerce B.Com, from University of Karachi, Pakistan, Year (1998).

Majors:

Auditing Business Analysis ■ Financial Accounting

 ■ Corporate & Business Law Taxation

Cost and Management Accounting

Technical Qualification:

Two year Diploma in Computer Science from NCR Education Center Session (2000) Covering following Courses:

Operating System: Unix

MS Windows 95, 98 & XP

Programming Software:

Oracle

C+ Language

Software Application:

MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint

Personal Profile:

Date of Birth : 04 April 1977

Marital Status : Married : Islam Religion : Pakistani **Nationality**

Reference:

Can be furnished on demand.